Guide to the The Penumbra Foundation Collection of Digitized Photography Manuals CAP.1
New York University Archives
- Digitized Publications
  - The Chemistry of Light and Photography, 1875; cap1_ref339; 1 bound volume (Object 187)
  - Men of Mark, 1877; cap1_ref340; 1 bound volume (Object 188)
  - The Philadelphia Photographer, 1871; cap1_ref341; 1 bound volume (Object 189)
  - The Philadelphia Photographer, 1882; cap1_ref342; 1 bound volume (Object 190)
  - The Philadelphia Photographer, 1870; cap1_ref343; 1 bound volume (Object 191)
  - The Wet Plate Collodion Process, undated; cap1_ref344; 1 bound volume (Object 192)
  - Photographic Materials, 1878; cap1_ref345; 1 bound volume (Object 193)
  - The Kodak on the Farm, 1909; cap1_ref346; 1 bound volume (Object 194)
  - Illustrated Catalog of Photographic Materials, 1899; cap1_ref347; 1 bound volume (Object 195)
  - Pictorial Landscape Photography, 1921; cap1_ref349; 1 bound volume (Object 196)
  - Telephotography, 1899; cap1_ref348; 1 bound volume (Object 197)
  - The Book of Photography, undated; cap1_ref350; 1 bound volume (Object 198)
  - Anthony's Photographic Bulletin, 1893; cap1_ref351; 1 bound volume (Object 199)
  - Reptar Lenses for Commercial Photography, cap1_ref360; Wollensak Opitcal Co. (Object 200)
  - Anthony's Photographic Bulletin, 1889; cap1_ref352; 1 bound volume (Object 201)
  - The Canadian Photographic Journal, 1895; cap1_ref353; 1 bound volume (Object 202)
  - The Developer, 1895; cap1_ref354; 1 bound volume (Object 203)
  - Cameras, Lenses, Shutters, & C., 1890; cap1_ref355; 1 bound volume (Object 204)
  - Lloyd's, MCM Photographic Encyclopedia, undated; cap1_ref356; 1 bound volume (Object 205)
  - Photographic Lenses, cap1_ref359 (Object 206)
  - Zeiss Photo Lenses, cap1_ref361 (Object 207)
  - Smith Soft Focus Lenses, cap1_ref362 (Object 208)
  - Photographic Lenses Shutters and Accessories, 1898; cap1_ref364; Bausch & Lomb Optical Company (Object 209)
  - Catalog of Cameras Photographic Supplies and Apparatus, 1911; cap1_ref365 (Object 210)
  - Lenses and Apparatus, 1860; cap1_ref363; Dallmeyer, J.H. (John Henry), 1830-1883 (Object 211)
  - Perspective as you please, 1937; cap1_ref366 (Object 212)
  - Historical Notices of the United Presbyterian Congregations, 1875; cap1_ref357; 1 bound volume (Object 213)
  - Appareils Photographiques, cap1_ref367 (Object 214)
  - Ernemann Cameras, 1913; cap1_ref368 (Object 215)
  - Photographic Lenses and Shutters, 1916-1917; cap1_ref369; Wollensak Opitcal Co. (Object 216)
  - Photographic Lenses and Shutters, 1912-1913; cap1_ref370; Wollensak Opitcal Co. (Object 217)
  - Goerz, October 1, 1916; cap1_ref371; Goerz, C. P. (Object 218)
  - Photo Lenses, cap1_ref372; Wollensak Opitcal Co. (Object 219)
  - Goerz American, 1951; cap1_ref373; Goerz, C. P. (Object 220)
  - Raptar Englarging Lenses, cap1_ref374; Wollensak Opitcal Co. (Object 221)
  - Raptar Telephoto and Wide Angle Lenses, cap1_ref375; Wollensak Opitcal Co. (Object 222)
  - Raptar Series II f4.5 Lenses, cap1_ref376; Wollensak Opitcal Co. (Object 223)
  - Raptar Lenses for Commercial Photography, cap1_ref377; Wollensak Opitcal Co. (Object 224)
  - Shutters with and without Synchronization, cap1_ref378; Wollensak Opitcal Co. (Object 225)
  - Wide-Angle Lenses, cap1_ref379 (Object 226)
  - Price List, 1903; cap1_ref380; Goerz, C. P. (Object 227)
  - Century Cameras, 1902; cap1_ref381 (Object 228)
  - Photographic Lenses and Korona Cameras, cap1_ref382 (Object 229)
  - Ross Homocentric Lens, January, 1910; cap1_ref383 (Object 230)
  - Goerz-Doppel-Anastigmat "Dagor", cap1_ref384; Goerz, C. P. (Object 231)
  - Photographic Lenses, 1931; cap1_ref385 (Object 232)
  - Objectifs et Appareils Optiques Pour La Photographie, 1913-1914; cap1_ref386 (Object 233)
  - Photographische Objective, 1855; cap1_ref387 (Object 234)
  - Photographic Lenses, 1912; cap1_ref388; Bausch & Lomb Optical Company (Object 235)
  - Manufacture Francaise D'Armes Et Cycles, cap1_ref389 (Object 236)
  - Prazisions Kameras Strative Zubehor, cap1_ref390 (Object 237)
  - Catalogue and Price List of Photographic Lenses and Prisims, April 1889; cap1_ref391 (Object 238)
  - Objectivas Cooke, 1912; cap1_ref392; Taylor, Taylor and Hobson, ltd. (Object 239)
  - Manufacture D'Optique De Precision, 1911; cap1_ref393 (Object 240)
  - Photographic Lenses and Shutters, 1922; cap1_ref394; Wollensak Opitcal Co. (Object 241)
  - Semi-Achromatic Lenses, cap1_ref395 (Object 242)
  - Photographic Lenses Catalog H, 1907; cap1_ref396; Bausch & Lomb Optical Company (Object 243)
  - Goerz Dogmar, cap1_ref397; Goerz, C. P. (Object 244)
  - A Startling New Studio Lens, cap1_ref398; Wollensak Opitcal Co. (Object 245)
  - The Worlds Finest Lenses, December, 1948; cap1_ref399; Taylor, Taylor and Hobson, ltd. (Object 246)
  - Schneider Xenar Xenotar, cap1_ref400 (Object 247)
  - Smith Soft Focus Lenses, cap1_ref401 (Object 248)
  - Photographic Lenses for the Amateur and Professional, cap1_ref402 (Object 249)
  - The Negative and the Print; Or, The Photographer's Guide, In the Field, Being A Text-Book For the Operator and Amateur, 1866; cuid1741 (Object 250)
    Scope and Contents
    Towler, John, M. D.
  - Chronicles of the Photographs of Spiritual Beings and Phenomena, 1882; cuid1742 (Object 251)
    Houghton, Miss
  - A Dictionary of Photography, 1867; cuid1743 (Object 252)
    Sutton, Thomas, B. A.; Dawson, George, M. A.
  - The Carbon Process; Or, How to Make Photographs in Pigments, 1868; cuid1744 (Object 253)
    Drummond, A. J.
  - A Practical Manual of the Collodion Process, 1857; cuid1745 (Object 254)
    Humphrey, S. D.
  - Dry Plate Photography; Or, The Tannin Process, 1865; cuid1746 (Object 255)
  - Landscape Photography; Or, A Complete and Easy Description, 1858; cuid1747 (Object 256)
    Otté, Joachim, F. G. S.
  - Micro-Photography, 1883; cuid1748 (Object 257)
    Malley, Cowley A., B.A., M.B., B.Ch., T.C.D.
  - Photographic Manipulation, Or System of Practice for the Chemical Department of the Portrait Gallery, 1864; cuid1749 (Object 258)
    Divine, S. R.
  - The Skylight and the Dark-Room, 1872; cuid1750 (Object 259)
    Anderson, Elbert
  - The Practical Printer, 1874; cuid1751 (Object 260)
    Hearn, Charles W.
  - Treatise of Photography on Collodion., 1858; cuid1752 (Object 261)
    Waldack, Charles; Peter Neff, JR
  - The Tannin Process., 1861; cuid1753 (Object 262)
    Russell, C.
  - The Modern Practice of Photography., 1868; cuid1754 (Object 263)
    Thomas, R. W., F.C.S.
  - The History and Practice of the Art of Photography, 1853; cuid1755 (Object 264)
    Snelling, Henry H.
  - Practical Hints on Photography: Its Chemistry and its Manipulations., 1860; cuid1756 (Object 265)
    Hockin, J B.
  - Photography. A New Treatise, Theoretical and Practical, 1855; cuid1757 (Object 266)
    Heath, A. S.,M.D.; Heath, A. H.
  - Practical Photography: On Glass and Paper, 1863; cuid1758 (Object 267)
    Bland and Co.
  - The Photograph Manual; A Practical Treatise, Containing the Cartes de Visite Process, 1863; cuid1759 (Object 268)
    Burgess, N. G.
  - Practical Photography: On Glass and Paper, 1859; cuid1760 (Object 269)
    Long, Charles A.
  - The Practice of Photography., 1857; cuid1761 (Object 270)
    Hunt, Robert, F.R.S.
  - The Art of Photography., 1854; cuid1762 (Object 271)
    Halleur, Hermann, Dr. G. C.
  - About Photography and Photographers., 1883; cuid1763 (Object 272)
    Pritchard, H. Baden, F.C.S.
  - Practical Portrait Photography, 1877; cuid1764 (Object 273)
    Heighway, William
  - Photographic Apparatus and Supplies, 12th edition, undated; cuid1765 (Object 274)
    Arrangement
    Hirsch and Kaye: San Francisco, CA.
  - Photographic Instruments and Equipment Cartograhic Apparatus, 1951; cuid1766 (Object 275)
    J. G. Saltzman, Inc.: New York, NY.
  - Nicola Perscheid - Objektiv, undated; cuid1767 (Object 276)
    Emil Busch A.-G..
  - Choosing the Right Lens For Large Format Photography, undated; cuid1768 (Object 277)
    Burke and James, Inc.: Chicago, IL; Pomona, CA; Linden, NJ.
  - Dallmeyer Lenses and Apparatus, undated; cuid1769 (Object 278)
    J. H. Dallmeyer, Ltd.: Willesden, London.
  - Goerz Lenses, undated; cuid1770 (Object 279)
    C. P. Goerz Optical Works: New York, NY; Chicago, IL.
  - Photographic Lenses and Acessories, undated; cuid1771 (Object 280)
    Bausch and Lomb Optical Company: Rochester, NY.
  - Photographic Lenses, 1910; cuid1772 (Object 281)
  - Optique et Mécanique de Précision, Catalogue A3, 1927; cuid1773 (Object 282)
    P. Guillaume and Cie.: Paris, France.
  - The Bodine Pictorial Lens, undated; cuid1774 (Object 283)
    Bodine, H. Oliver. The Photo Crafts Shops: Racine, WI.
  - Illustrated Descriptive Price List of Photographic Apparatus, 1972; cuid1775 (Object 284)
    Classic Photographic Apparatus: Simsbury, CT.
  - Dallmeyer Lenses for Amateur Cinematography, undated; cuid1776 (Object 285)
    Messrs. Harringtons, Ltd.: Hobart, Australia.
  - Century Cameras, 1908; cuid1777 (Object 286)
    Eastman Kodak Company: Rochester, NY.
  - Angulon f: 6,8, undated; cuid1778 (Object 287)
    Jos. Schneider and Co.: Kreuznach, Germany.
  - Rodenstock Imagon, undated; cuid1779 (Object 288)
    Optische Werke G. Rodenstock: Munich, Germany.
  - Mystery of Filters, 1939; cuid1780 (Object 289)
    Harrison and Harrison: Hollywood, CA.
  - Rexo "Every Click a Picture", 1919; cuid1781 (Object 290)
    Burke and James, Inc.: Chicago, IL; New York, NY.
  - Photographic Materials, Mail Order Catalog No. 131, 1931; cuid1782 (Object 291)
    George Murphy, Inc.: New York, NY; Chicago, IL.
  - Voigtländer Lenses, undated; cuid1783 (Object 292)
    Voigtländer and Sohn: Chicago, IL; New York, NY.
  - Ross Lenses, 1950; cuid1784 (Object 293)
    Barnet Ensign Ross, Ltd.: London, England.
  - Graflex and Graphic Cameras, 1920; cuid1785 (Object 294)
  - Graflex and Graphic Cameras, 1927; cuid1786 (Object 295)
    The Folmer Graflex Corporation: Rochester, NY.
  - Graflex and Graphic Cameras, 1916; cuid1787 (Object 296)
  - Graflex and Graphic Cameras, 1913; cuid1788 (Object 297)
  - Graflex and Speed Graphic Cameras, A Guide to More Interesting Pictures, 1941; cuid1789 (Object 298)
  - Graflex and Graphic, Focal Plane Shutter Photography, 1936; cuid1790 (Object 299)
  - Graflex and Graphic Cameras, Eastman Supplies, 1926; cuid1791 (Object 300)
  - Instruction Manual for Graflex Cameras; Series B, RB Series B, RB Series D, RB Super D, Auto, RB Auto, Auto Jr., RB Tele, RB Jr., undated; cuid1792 (Object 301)
    Graflex, Inc.: Rochester, NY.
  - Color Photography with Autochrom Plates, 19th edition, undated; cuid1793 (Object 302)
    R. J. Fitzsimons: New York, NY.
  - Voigtländer, undated; cuid1794 (Object 303)
    Voigtländer and Sohn.
  - Berühmte Voigtländer Objektive, undated; cuid1795 (Object 304)
  - Voigtländer Lenses, undated; cuid1796 (Object 305)
    Voigtländer and Sohn, A. G.: New York, NY.
  - Catalogue of Photographic Lenses; Catalogue of Photographic Objectives, undated; cuid1797 (Object 306)
    The Voigtlaender and Son Optical Company: New York, NY.
  - How to Choose and Use A Lens, 1937; cuid1798 (Object 307)
    Frappie, Frank R. American Photographic Publishing Company: Boston, MA.
  - Century Graphic Instruction Manual, undated; cuid1799 (Object 308)
  - Why A Graflex?; The Camera For More Interesting Pictures, undated; cuid1800 (Object 309)
    Folmer Graflex Corporation: Rochester, NY.
  - Super Technika; The Camera for the Most Exacting Dmenads; Linhof, undated; cuid1801 (Object 310)
    Nikolaus Karpf KG., Präzisions - Kamera - Werke: Munich, Germany.
  - Kodak Lenses, Shutters and Porta Lenses, 3rd edition, 1948; cuid1802 (Object 311)
  - A Short Story of Technical Glassware, 1938; cuid1803 (Object 312)
    Corning Glass Works: Corning, NY.
  - The Eagle Eye of Your Camera, 1932; cuid1804 (Object 313)
    Carl Zeiss/Jena.
  - Goerz Lenses, 1915; cuid1805 (Object 314)
    C. P. Goerz American Optical Company: New York, NY.
  - A Catalog of Taylor-Hobson Cooke Lenses, Catalog B, 1938; cuid1806 (Object 315)
    Eastman Kodak Stores Company: Chicago, IL.
  - Wollensak Lenses for the Advanced Amateur; A Catalogue of Photographic Lenses and Shutters, undated; cuid1807 (Object 316)
    Wollensak Optical Co.: Rochester, NY.
  - Goerz Cameras and Lenses, undated; cuid1808 (Object 317)
    C. P. Goerz Optical Works, Ltd.: London, England.
  - Goerz Precison Lenses for Professional and Amateur Photography, Photo-Engraving, Movie Making, undated; cuid1809 (Object 318)
    C. P. Goerz American Optical Co.: New York, NY.
  - Dallmeyer Wide-Angle Anastigmat Lens, undated; cuid1810 (Object 319)
    Great Britain.
  - Plaubel Makina, undated; cuid1811 (Object 320)
    Plaubel: Frankfurt, Germany.
  - Brooks- Plaubel Veriwide 100, undated; cuid1812 (Object 321)
  - Directions for use of the Makina, undated; cuid1813 (Object 322)
  - Instructions For the Use of the Personal Camera Makina IIS, undated; cuid1814 (Object 323)
    Photo Marketing Corporation: New York, NY.
  - Instructions For the Use of the Personal Camera Plaubel Makina II, 1934; cuid1815 (Object 324)
    USA.
  - Illustrated Catalogue of the Celebrated Voigtländer and Son's Portrait-Lenses and Euryscopes, 1887, 1972; cuid1816 (Object 325)
    Andre Farkas: Norwalk, CT.
  - Plaubel Peco Junior, undated; cuid1817 (Object 326)
  - The Simplified Graflex, 1929; cuid1818 (Object 327)
  - Kodak Lenses, Shutters and Porta Lenses, 5th edition, 1955; cuid1819 (Object 328)
  - The Rodenstock IMAGON Lens, undated; cuid1820 (Object 329)
  - Illustrated Catalogue of the Celebrated Voigtländer and Son's Portrait-Lenses and Euryscopes, 1890; cuid1821 (Object 330)
    Benjamin French and Co.: Boston, MA.
  - Voigtländer Lenses and Cameras, 1914; cuid1822 (Object 331)
    Voightländer and Sohn: Chicago, IL; New York, NY.
  - Graflex and Graphic Cameras, 1911; cuid1823 (Object 332)
  - Goerz 1886-1911, undated; cuid1824 (Object 333)
    Imberg and Lefson: Berlin, Germany.
  - Photographic Lenses by Ross London, 1946; cuid1825 (Object 334)
    The Optical Works: London, England.
  - The Optics of Photography and Photographic Lenses, 1904; cuid1826 (Object 335)
    Taylor, J. Traill. Whittaker and Co.: London, England; New York, NY.
  - Dallmeyer Lenses, undated; cuid1827 (Object 336)
    Herbert and Huesgen Co.: New York, NY.
  - Photographic Lenses and Shutters, Catalog No. 30, undated; cuid1828 (Object 337)
    Wollensak Optical Company: Rochester, NY.
  - Photographic Lenses and Shutters, Cataog No. 34, undated; cuid1829 (Object 338)
  - Wollensak, Velostigmats, Enlarging Lenses and Color Filters, undated; cuid1830 (Object 339)
  - A Catalogue of the Photographic Lenses and Shutters made by the Wollensak Optical Company, 1913; cuid1831 (Object 340)
  - Wollensak Photo Lenses, Catalog No. 41, undated; cuid1832 (Object 341)
  - Wollensak Photo Lenses, Catalog No. 35, undated; cuid1833 (Object 342)
  - Supplement Graflex Catalog, Lenses, 1930; cuid1834 (Object 343)
  - A Catalogue of Photographic Lenses and Shutters, 1920, 1919; cuid1835 (Object 344)
  - Goerz Lenses for Photographic Accuracy, undated; cuid1836 (Object 345)
  - The Eagle of Your Eye; Zeiss Objectives, undated; cuid1837 (Object 346)
    Carl Zeiss/Jena: Germany.
  - Grafmatic Film Holder; Instruction Manual, undated; cuid1838 (Object 347)
  - Graflex and Graphic; Focal Plane Shutter Photography, undated; cuid1839 (Object 348)
  - Graflex: The American Made Camera for More Interesting Pictures, 1936; cuid1840 (Object 349)
  - Graflex and Graphic Cameras, 1915; cuid1841 (Object 350)
  - Graflex and Graphic Cameras, 1925; cuid1842 (Object 351)
  - Graflex and Graphic Cameras, 1913; cuid1843 (Object 352)
  - Graflex and Graphic Cameras, 1925; cuid1844 (Object 353)
  - Ross Lenses, Cameras, etc., undated; cuid1845 (Object 354)
    Ross Ltd.Optical Works: London, England.
  - Dallmeyer Lenses for Amateur Cinematography, Their Choice and Use, undated; cuid1846 (Object 355)
    England.
  - Illustrated Catalogue of Photographic Apparatus, Lenses and Materials, No. 29, undated; cuid1847 (Object 356)
    Eastman Kodak Stores, Inc.: Philadelphia, PA.
  - Introducing the IMAGON By Josef Folding, undated; cuid1848 (Object 357)
    Optische Werke, G. Rodenstock: Munich, Germany.
  - Goerz Lenses for Photographic Accuracy, undated; cuid1849 (Object 358)
  - Goerz Photoengraving Lenses, undated; cuid1850 (Object 359)
  - Catalogue of the "N. and G." Cameras, Shutters, Changing-Boxes and other Photographic Apparatus, undated; cuid1851 (Object 360)
    Newman and Guardia, Ltd.: London, England.
  - Portrait Lenses for the Professional Photographer, undated; cuid1852 (Object 361)
    Bausch and Lomb Optical Co.: Rochester, NY.
  - Photographic Lenses, Catalog H, 1907; cuid1853 (Object 362)
  - Goerz Kameras and Objektive, 1886-1911, 1994; cuid1854 (Object 363)
    Verlag der H. Lindemanns Buchhandlung: Stuttgart, Germany.
  - Taylor-Hobson Lenses for 8mm. and 16 mm. Cine Cameras, undated; cuid1855 (Object 364)
    G. B. Equipments Limited: London, England.
  - Carl Zeiss: Jena; Series IX. Double-Amatar f/6.8, 1910; cuid1856 (Object 365)
    Carl Zeiss: Jena.
  - Zeiss Protar Convertible Objective, Series IV., 1908; cuid1857 (Object 366)
    Carl Zeiss: Jena: London, Berlin, Hamburg, Frankfort, Vienna, St. Petersburg.
  - Goerz' Doppel-Anastigmat; Sere IIa, F: 5,5, undated; cuid1858 (Object 367)
    Optische Anstalt C. P. Goerz: Berlin-Friedenau, Germany.
  - Extrait du Catalogue Général; Matériel d'Atelier Pour Photographes Professionnels, undated; cuid1859 (Object 368)
    Demaria-Lapierre: Paris, France.
  - Multi Speed Shutters, 1912; cuid1860 (Object 369)
    The Multi Speed Shutter Co.: New York, NY.
  - Catalogue of Professional and Commercial Photographic Apparatus and Sundries, undated; cuid1861 (Object 370)
  - Korona Cameras; Photographic Lenses, 1920; cuid1862 (Object 371)
    Gundlach-Manhattan Optical Company: Rochester, NY.
  - Étude Élémentaire de L'Objectif des Chambres et Obturateurs Photographiques, undated; cuid1863 (Object 372)
    Ménetrat, Georges. Éditions Charles-Mendel: Paris, France.
  - Lucien Leroy 16th Édition, 1916-1917, undated; cuid1864 (Object 373)
    Lucien Leroy: Paris, France.
  - Photographic Lenses and Accessories, undated; cuid1865 (Object 374)
  - One Lens Investment That Fills Many Needs, undated; cuid1866 (Object 375)
  - Graflex and Graphic Cameras, 1913; cuid1867 (Object 376)
  - Berühmte Voigtländer Objektive, undated; cuid1868 (Object 377)
    .
  - Derogy: Catalogue des Chambres noires et Pieds, undated; cuid1869 (Object 378)
    L. Lhen: Paris, France.
  - Catalogue Spécial des Appareils des Grandes Marques concernant la Photographie, la T.S.F., les Phonographes, les Machines a Écrire, 1927; cuid1870 (Object 379)
    L'Intermédiaire; G. Loisel, Muller and Champagne: Paris, France.
  - E. Krauss, Optique et Mécanique de Précision; Objectifs et Appareils Photographiques, undated; cuid1871 (Object 380)
    E. Krauss: Paris, France.
  - Catalogue of Photographic Lenses and Apparatus, also Telescopes and Prismatic Binoculars., 1905; cuid1872 (Object 381)
    J. H. Dallmeyer Ltd.: London, England.
  - Catalogue of Photographic Lenses. and Apparatus., undated; cuid1873 (Object 382)
  - The Eagle Eye of Your Camera; Zeiss Tessars, 1932; cuid1874 (Object 383)
    Carl Zeiss: Jena: London, England.
  - The Latest Rollei Equipment, undated; cuid1875 (Object 384)
    Franke and Heidecke: Braunschweig, Germany.
  - Wide-Angle Rolleiflex, undated; cuid1876 (Object 385)
  - Goerz Celor, The Practical Speed Lens, 1914; cuid1877 (Object 386)
  - Goerz Lenses, undated; cuid1878 (Object 387)
  - Graflex and Graphic Cameras, 1914; cuid1879 (Object 388)
  - Description and Price List of the Holostigmat Lens, undated; cuid1880 (Object 389)
    W. Watson and Sons: London, England.
  - Nikkor Lenses for Large Format Cameras, undated; cuid1881 (Object 390)
    Nikon: Garden City, NY.
  - Photographic List, Cameras, Lenses, Outfits, 1914; cuid1882 (Object 391)
    Ross, Ltd.: London, England.
  - Wollensak Photo Lenses, Catalog No. 41, undated; cuid1883 (Object 392)